westpac.co.nz 2019-12-21

# Westpac NZ - Legal Information

**EU residents can view our[GDPR Privacy Policy here](https://www.westpac.co.nz/assets/Personal/Westpac-New-Zealand-EU-Data-Protection-Policy.pdf).**

 **You can download a copy of our[Privacy Policy here](https://www.westpac.co.nz/assets/Personal/Westpac-Privacy-Policy.pdf)[]() or read it below.**

At Westpac we are committed to your privacy. In this Privacy Policy we explain how **_Westpac_** (Westpac New Zealand Limited and its NZ operations) collects, stores, uses and shares your personal information.

Personal information is information about an identifiable individual. It includes information that could be used to identify you, such as your name and contact details. It also includes credit information as defined in the Credit Reporting Privacy Code 2004, essentially information that has a bearing on credit that you have applied for or that is being provided to you.

This Privacy Policy applies to all products and services made available in New Zealand by the **_Westpac Group_** (comprising Westpac Banking Corporation ABN 33 007 457 141, Westpac and all related entities of both), including those provided electronically. By using any of these products and services you are permitting us to collect, store, use and share your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### Summary of how we manage your personal information

[ **1\. Collection:**](https://www.westpac.co.nz/who-we-are/about-westpac-new-zealand/westpac-legal-information/#collection) We collect the personal information you provide to us either directly or from your computer, mobile or other device. We may also collect your personal information from a range of third parties, including service providers. If you choose not to provide the personal information we request then we may not be able to offer all our services to you.

[ **2\. Use and Disclosure:**](https://www.westpac.co.nz/who-we-are/about-westpac-new-zealand/westpac-legal-information/#use) We use your personal information for a range of purposes including for the provision of products and services, to better understand your preferences and to conduct and develop our business. Where authorised, we may share your personal information with other members of the Westpac Group, credit reporting, governmental and law enforcement agencies and third party service providers.

[ **3\. Storage:**](https://www.westpac.co.nz/who-we-are/about-westpac-new-zealand/westpac-legal-information/#storage) If we collect personal information about you, we will store it in secure data storage facilities usually located in New Zealand or Australia.

[ **4\. Cookies:**](https://www.westpac.co.nz/who-we-are/about-westpac-new-zealand/westpac-legal-information/#cookies) We use cookies and similar technologies on our websites and other digital services to improve those services and enhance your online experience.

[ **5\. Access & Complaints:**](https://www.westpac.co.nz/who-we-are/about-westpac-new-zealand/westpac-legal-information/#access) You may request access and corrections to your personal information.

### 1\. Collection of your personal information 

Most of your personal information that we collect will come **directly from you** when you deal with Westpac either in person, remotely or in writing. The type of information we collect will depend on the product or service in question and may include:

  * your identification and contact details, including your name, (e)mail address, phone number, specimen signature, date of birth and Inland Revenue Department number;
  * information collected in relation to your use of our online banking services, websites (including third party websites containing interactive Westpac content and Westpac-branded social media pages), mobile applications and ATMs ( ** _Digital Services_** ), including your user name and login credentials, activity logs, IP address and cookie, device, browser and operating system identifiers (including device location identifiers where you agree to let us access that information);
  * your employment details, financial position, credit record and banking transaction history;
  * your queries, complaints and other written or verbal communications with us. When you’re dealing with any member of Westpac by telephone or live web or video chat service, your conversation may be recorded for training or verification purposes; 
  * in an insurance context, information about what is being insured, any insurance policy beneficiaries, your health, financial and insurance history and information required for processing claims; 
  * details you have shared publicly on social media platforms, which may be used to supplement our customer databases and for marketing and business development purposes; and 
  * any other information that any member of the Westpac Group is required by law to collect about you.

We may also collect your personal information from **third parties** , including:

  * other members of the Westpac Group;
  * where that information has been made publicly available, social media platforms and public information service providers such as public registers;
  * commercial information service providers such as credit reporting agencies, market researchers, data and/or analytics providers and advertising networks; 
  * third parties providing offers, products and services available to you as a Westpac Group customer; 
  * your representatives, such as your legal or financial adviser;
  * your employer; 
  * insurance providers and other organisations operating in the insurance industry, such as underwriters, health care providers, claims administrators and investigators; 
  * selected business partners to improve, optimise and personalise your experience of our products and services; and 
  * any other sources considered appropriate by any member of the Westpac Group in relation to the provision of credit.

### 2\. Using and sharing your personal information – purposes

 **For the purposes set out below at 2.1-2.4, Westpac** and any member of the Westpac Group may **use and share your personal information** with a range of organisations including other members of the Westpac Group (including their agents and anyone who provides services to them, subject to appropriate confidentiality obligations); your representatives and anyone you make a payment to; authorities such as regulators, government agencies, courts or the police; other financial services organisations; fraud bureaus, credit reference and debt recovery agencies; external dispute resolution schemes; brokers and referrers; anyone in connection with a reorganisation, sale or acquisition of any Westpac Group member’s business; payments systems operators; our agents; and third parties bound by confidentiality obligations such as service providers, suppliers, business partners and certain sub-contractors to:

 **2.1 Provide our products and services and administer our relationship with you, including to:**

  * assess whether to give you a particular product or service, including by confirming your identity, residence, employment and financial status and to make all necessary enquiries about any information you have given us in relation to any product or service that we are providing;
  * provide our products and service to you, including communicating with you throughout the life of your relationship with Westpac about any changes to our product and services; 
  * provide customer support, including contacting you to offer assistance with online applications (including those you do not complete);
  * improve, optimise and personalise your experience of our services; and 
  * if you are a joint account holder, enable any member of the Westpac Group to share your personal information relating to your joint account with the other joint account holder(s).

**2.2 Comply with laws and regulation, including to:**

  * enable any member of the Westpac Group to comply with any New Zealand or overseas laws, rules or regulations, including any that are reasonably expected to be implemented (including to enable the government of New Zealand to comply with any agreement between it and the government of another country); and
  * share personal information with the police, government agencies in New Zealand or overseas or other financial institutions, where any member of the Westpac Group reasonably believes that the disclosure will assist it to comply with any New Zealand or overseas laws, rules or regulations or will assist in the investigation, detection and/or prevention of fraud, money laundering or other criminal offences.

**2.3 Understand your credit position, including to:**

  * enable any member of the Westpac Group to conduct credit checks when you apply for, open and operate accounts and loans. That may involve giving your personal information to credit reporting agencies, which collect information about your credit history and compile reports about your suitability as a borrower. Those reports can be used to confirm your identity, verify your current credit obligations and help assess your ability to meet repayment obligations;
  * enable credit reporting agencies to update their credit reporting databases and provide updates to members of the Westpac Group and their other customers on your credit record and other information about you that could impact your ongoing relationship (including without limitation, updates notifying that other people have made enquiry of the credit reporting agency about you); and to collect any money owed by you.

**2.4 Research and market products and services, including to:**

  * Conduct market research and analysis about our brand, offers, Westpac Group products or services either ourselves or using service providers, both while you are a customer and for a reasonable time afterwards; 
  * unless you ask us not to, make available and send you information about the full range of offers, products and services offered by any member of the Westpac Group, including to: 
      * enable selected third parties to present you with offers, advertisements and/or products or services that we believe may be of interest to you; and 
      * provide you with information about events, appeals and organisations sponsored by any member of the Westpac Group.

We may contact you by various means, including mail, telephone, email, SMS/text message and online banking. You can ask us not to use your personal information for marketing purposes either by updating your “Name and email preferences” in the “profile” section of Westpac Online Banking or by calling 0800 400 600. You can also unsubscribe from electronic messages received from us by following the instructions provided in the message.

 **In addition to the reasons set out above** , Westpac Group members may also share your personal information with third parties (subject to appropriate confidentiality obligations) where you have **consented to that information being shared** or the reason for doing so is **connected to the purpose of collecting** the personal information.

Where Westpac receives a request for information from the police or any government agency, it may confirm whether a specified person is or was a customer, but will not provide any other customer information except with a production order, with the customer’s consent, where necessary to prevent or lessen a serious threat to health or safety, or as required by law.

### 3\. Storage of your personal information

Your personal information will be stored either **in paper files or electronically in secure data centres** located in New Zealand or overseas that are owned either by the Westpac Group or its external service providers.

We use a range of **physical and electronic data security measures** to protect information from loss and unauthorised use, access, modification or disclosure. For example:

  * access to information systems is controlled through identity and access management; 
  * employees are bound by information security policies and are required to keep information secure; 
  * all employees are required to complete training about information security; and 
  * we regularly monitor and review our compliance (and our service providers’ compliance) with internal policies and industry best practice.

Personal information collected through use of our online banking services is passed through a secure Westpac server using encryption technology to help ensure that this information is protected when sent over the internet. Further, all stored personal information is protected from unauthorised access through the use of recognised security procedures such as passwords, PINs and biometric-based forms of access.

### 4\. Cookies

We use cookies and other digital tracking tools ( _ **cookies**_ ) on the Digital Services. A cookie is a small piece of data sent by a website to the browser on your device to help us collect and store information about your use of the Digital Services. **That will include your personal information if you log in to our online banking services.** Some cookies are installed only temporarily while others may remain for a period of time, covering multiple sessions.

Westpac and our service providers, such as Adobe, Google and DoubleClick, use cookies on the Digital Services for various purposes, including:

  *  **Security:** to verify online banking customers and carry out other essential security checks that enable us to offer you a secure and reliable online banking service; 
  * **Efficiency:** to enable us to operate our Digital Services efficiently and with a high level of functionality; 
  * **Measurement & analysis:** to measure website traffic and usage patterns on the Digital Services and to collect information about your interactions with those services and Westpac content on third party websites. That information is then used to analyse and improve our services, analyse user behaviour and measure the effectiveness of our marketing initiatives and services;
  * **Advertising:** to deliver advertisements that we believe are relevant to your interests both on the Digital Services and on non-Westpac websites using information we hold about you;
  * **Personalisation:** to understand your interests and preferences so we can tailor the content of the Digital Services to your likely interests and provide you with a more relevant personalised online experience, improve our services and identify suitable offers, products and services from Westpac, Westpac Group and third parties that we believe may interest you; and
  * **Communication:** in the context of our mobile applications, to record unique identifiers associated with your device in order to send relevant messages to you. Those unique identifiers may include the device ID, IP address, MAC address or IMEI number, your activity within the app and your network location.

For those purposes, we may combine information collected from your use of the Digital Services with other information we hold about you, such as personal information available to us once you log in to Westpac Online Banking, personal information collected through our banking relationship with you, information we collect from third parties and information that is publicly available.

 **4.1 How to control cookie settings on your device**

We recommend you enable cookies on your browsers in order to enjoy all the features of our Digital Services. **You won’t be able to use our secure online banking services if you block some or all cookies**. In addition, other websites and applications may not function properly. You can block advertising cookies by manually adjusting the cookie settings on your website browser - see the “Help” menu on your browser for details. To opt out of receiving personalised messages on the Digital Services and the aggregation and analysis of data about your visits to the Digital Services, you will need to install a special cookie on your browser that identifies you have opted out. You can do this by visiting [westpac.co.nz/nocookies](https://www.westpac.co.nz/nocookies). You will not be able to opt out in this manner if you have previously blocked advertising cookies in your website browser. Opt-out cookies are specific to your browser and device and will need to be re-set on different devices and browsers. To learn more about cookies, visit [allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

### 5\. Accessing and correcting your personal information

Westpac will do its best to ensure your personal information is accurate. **You are responsible for promptly informing Westpac of any change of your personal details** (including your name, address, telephone, mobile or facsimile numbers and email address).

You can contact us to request access, or that corrections are made, to the personal information we hold about you. A reasonable fee may be charged to **process** your request, covering activities such as locating, collating and supplying the information to you.

Under the Privacy Act, in some circumstances we do not have to give you access to or correct your personal information. If that is the case, we will explain why and provide information about how you can complain should you wish to do so.

### 6\. Resolving your privacy concerns and complaints – your rights

Your satisfaction is our priority so if you have a concern or complaint, please let us know and we’ll do our best to resolve it right away. If you’re unhappy with our response, you may wish to contact either the **Privacy Commissioner** at [privacy.org.nz](http://www.privacy.org.nz%20/) or the **Banking Ombudsman** at [bankomb.org.nz](http://www.bankomb.org.nz/).

### 7\. How to contact us

  * In person at a branch (you can use our handy branch locator tool at [westpac.co.nz/redpages](https://www.westpac.co.nz/who-we-are/find-contact-us/find-a-branch-or-atm/)) 
  * By phone on 0800 400 600, 7 days a week, 7 am - 11 pm 
  * Online at [westpac.co.nz/feedback](https://www.westpac.co.nz/who-we-are/find-contact-us/feedback/) 
  * In writing to the Westpac Privacy Officer, Freepost 125 436, P.O. Box 934, Auckland 1140, New Zealand.

### 8\. Changes to this Privacy Policy

From time to time we may make changes to this Privacy Policy, for example to record any changes to the way we handle personal information or the functionality of our Digital Services. Notice of any changes will be given at least 14 days in advance, by posting the updated Privacy Policy on our website. Your continued use of our products and services after the end of the notice period will be taken as acceptance of the updated Privacy Policy.

### 9\. Applicable law

This Privacy Policy is governed by New Zealand law. Your personal information will be collected, used, stored, shared and retained in accordance with this Privacy Policy and New Zealand law. The courts of New Zealand have non-exclusive jurisdiction.

This policy is current as at **15 April 2019**.

### Information you must read before proceeding into the Westpac Website.

(If you proceed to any other page of the Westpac Website, you will be treated as having read and accepted the information on this page)

  1. This website (including the internet banking services) is presented by the Westpac New Zealand Limited, however some of the products on the website are provided by Westpac Banking Corporation ABN 33 007 457 141 (New Zealand division).
  2. References on this website to Westpac are references to Westpac New Zealand Limited, or to Westpac Banking Corporation.
  3. Westpac Institutional Bank refers to the brand under which products and services are provided by either Westpac Banking Corporation ABN 33 007 457 141 or Westpac New Zealand Limited (company number 1763882). Any product or service made available by Westpac New Zealand Limited does not represent an offer from Westpac Banking Corporation or any of its subsidiaries (other than Westpac New Zealand Limited). Neither Westpac Banking Corporation nor its other subsidiaries guarantee or otherwise support the offer or the performance of Westpac New Zealand Limited. Westpac New Zealand is not an authorised deposit- taking institution for the purposes of Australian prudential standards.
  4. The information on this website is preliminary and general information only. It is subject to change at any time. You must not rely on it as being complete, accurate, or up to date. You should obtain independent professional legal and/or financial advice before you rely on any of the information.
  5. Information on this website has been prepared in accordance with New Zealand law for the supply of services in New Zealand only. Therefore, any services referred to in this website are only offered to persons resident in New Zealand.
  6. Westpac is not, in this website, making any offer to enter into any transaction or relationship with you. For full details of up to date service information, charges, interest rates, terms and conditions, and any special offers you should visit a Westpac branch in New Zealand, or telephone your Westpac branch.
  7. Westpac is not responsible for the information on any other site accessed via this website; that information is the responsibility of the owner of that site. Westpac has no control over it. Links to other sites are provided for convenience only and do not represent any endorsement by Westpac of the services offered by the site owner.
  8. Please contact Westpac for prior permission if you wish to create a hypertext link to any page on this website. If you create a link to this website, you remain fully responsible for any consequences of that link, whether direct or indirect and you will protect Westpac against all loss, damage, liability, costs or expense arising from or in connection with the link.
  9. When providing your personal information over the Internet, you should remember that the Internet is not a secure environment. Any personal information collected by Westpac may be used by Westpac to provide information to you about the full range of financial services offered by Westpac and its related companies, as well as to assist Westpac to create a statistical picture of its customers. Westpac will take steps to ensure your personal information is held securely by Westpac, and you may request access to, and correction of, all such information by contacting Westpac's privacy officer.
  10. You agree that any ideas, suggestions or comments you provide to Westpac through this website will be treated as non-confidential and non-proprietary to you. Such ideas, suggestions and comments will become the exclusive property of Westpac and may be used by Westpac in whole or in part in any manner whatsoever without notice or compensation to you.
  11. The copyright in this website is owned by Westpac New Zealand Limited. You may electronically reproduce and store the website’s contents solely for the purposes of viewing the website, or saving its content. However, if you want to display or distribute the content or any of the pages of the website in public or in such a way that they will be accessible to the public (including reproduction in any form on the Internet), you must first obtain Westpac’s permission.
  12. Access to the Westpac's internet banking services is restricted to authorised users only. Unauthorised users may be subject to criminal or civil prosecution under the laws of New Zealand or under the laws of the country from which unauthorised access took place.
  13. These Website Terms of Use incorporate [Westpac's Privacy Policy which is available here](https://www.westpac.co.nz/assets/Personal/Westpac-Privacy-Policy.pdf).

5 December 2013

#### General Terms & Conditions - Effective 18 February 2019

#### Supplier Terms & Conditions - Effective 4 November 2016

Applicable for suppliers supplying goods or services to Westpac not currently covered by an existing agreement.

**22 October 2019**

 **Purchase Profile Terms and Conditions**

The Purchase Profile Terms and Conditions are changing, effective 5 November 2019. 

The change relates to adding the ability for Westpac to withdraw the service.

Please refer to [Purchase Profile Terms and Conditions](https://www.westpac.co.nz/assets/Business-Payments/Purchase-Profile-Terms-and-Conditions-2019-Westpac-NZ.pdf).

 **20 September 2019**

 **Cheque deposit clearance times**

From 1 October 2019, industry cheque processing times are changing and this may mean that if you deposit a cheque, access to your funds will take longer than you are used to. 

Please remember that cheque deposits can take up to 5 business days to clear. 

Please refer to [Westpac General Terms and Conditions](https://www.westpac.co.nz/assets/Who-we-are/About-Westpac-NZ/Westpac-General-Terms-and-Conditions.pdf) or learn more[](https://westpac.custhelp.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/924/kw/cheque%20clearance) about [cheque clearance times](https://westpac.custhelp.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/924/kw/cheque%20clearance).

 **17 July 2019**

From 1 August 2019, we’re changing some of our home lending, personal overdraft and credit & debit card fees.

This includes reducing the Foreign Currency Fee on personal credit and debit cards from 2.5% to 1.4% of the transaction amount and removing the monthly Line of Credit Charge for overdraft facilities on personal transaction accounts.

While the manual transaction fee on Choices Home Loan accounts is increasing from $0.65 to $2.50, this fee will be capped at $5 per month per account.

You can see all the fee changes below.

| 

**Current Fee**

| 

**New Fee**  
  
---|---|---  
  
**Home lending  **  
  
Choices Home Loan establishment fee

| 

$400

| 

$250  
  
Documentation fee  
(Choices home loan top-up, redocumentation)

| 

$170

| 

$125  
  
Security amendment fee

| 

$170

| 

No charge  
  
Choices Everyday monthly account fee

| 

$9.95

| 

$5  
  
Choices Offset monthly fee (per loan)

| 

$10

| 

No charge  
  
Choices Home Loan – electronic transaction

| 

$0.40

| 

Free  
  
Choices Home Loan – manual transaction

| 

$0.65

| 

$2.50  
(capped at $5 per month)  
  
**Personal credit/debit card  **  
  
Hotpoints Platinum Mastercard annual account fee

| 

$125 p.a.  
(charged 6 monthly at $62.50)

| 

$119 p.a.  
(charged 6 monthly at $59.50)  
  
Airpoints Platinum Mastercard annual account fee

| 

$145 p.a.  
(charged 6 monthly at $72.50)

| 

$150 p.a.  
(charged 6 monthly at $75.00)  
  
Foreign currency fee

| 

2.5% of transaction amount

| 

1.4% of transaction amount  
  
**Personal overdraft service fees  **  
  
Line of credit charge (LCC) for overdraft facilities

| 

0.1% per month   
(minimum $5)

| 

No charge  
  
**Other service fees**  
  
Security registration/discharge

| 

$100

| 

$105  
  
Administration fee for a  fixed rate loan prepayment

| 

$50

| 

$49  
  
Rate demand fee

| 

$50

| 

$12  
  
**17 June 2019**

From 2 July 2019 outward International Telegraphic Transfers sent by you to another bank on Westpac One or Business Online will be $10 per transfer (down from $20).

Please refer to [**Other Service Fees**](https://www.westpac.co.nz/managing-your-money/resources/fees/other-service-fees/) to view service and account fees.

 **31 May 2019**

 **We’re changing our savings accounts to give you more flexibility while you save.**

From 2 July 2019, we’ll be changing the name of our Online Bonus Saver account to Westpac Bonus Saver and our Online Bonus Saver PIE account to Westpac Bonus Saver PIE with key changes to some of the features.

 **Here’s what’s new with the Westpac Bonus Saver and Westpac Bonus Saver PIE accounts:**

  *  **How bonus interest/return works:** You will be able to make unlimited withdrawals as long as on the last day of the business month your balance is $20 greater than on the last business day of the month prior. The $20 excludes interest earned on the account and/or Westpac fees charged to the account.
  * **Paper statement fee:** If you choose to receive paper statements you’ll be charged a $1.50 paper statement fee. Receiving your statements electronically will continue to be free.
  * **Manual transactions:** Branch deposits and withdrawals now available. There will a branch assisted withdrawal fee of $2.50 for each transaction. 
  * **Fee exemption for people under 19 or 65 and over:** If you are under 19 or 65 years or over you won’t pay the paper statement fee or manual withdrawal fee.
  * **Increased accessibility:** Payments can be made directly out of the account within Westpac One online banking, without the need to transfer money via a Westpac transaction account.
  * **No minimum balance (Westpac Bonus Saver PIE only):** There will no longer be a minimum balance amount required. However, if your account balance is $0 (being 0 units) you will not have any interest in the fund.

Please refer to the updated [Westpac Cash PIE Fund Term Sheet](https://www.westpac.co.nz/assets/Personal/Bank-Accounts/Cash-PIE/Westpac_Bonus_Saver_Cash_Pie_Fund_Term_Sheet-2July19.pdf) for further information.

 **24 May 2019**

 **Changes to Credit Card Conditions of Use - How payments will be applied**

As part of our mission to simplify our products and services, from 11 June 2019 we’re changing how payments are applied to your credit card account.

Any payments you make will first go to charges and interest accrued, then to cash advances and purchases, followed by balance transfers. 

If you have a balance transfer on your credit card, this change means any balance transfer amount won’t start being paid off until any cash advances or purchases made on your card have been paid in full. Previously, payments went towards your balance transfer before cash advances and purchases.

See the Application of Payments section in the Conditions of Use applicable to your credit card below, effective from 11 June 2019.

We’ve also made some minor wording changes to the Conditions of Use, to ensure our definitions are as clear as possible.

If you need more information you can always come in to any branch for a chat or contact us on **0800 888 111**.

 **23 May 2019**

The Westpac One App Terms and Conditions are changing, effective from App Version 14.4. The changes will relate to the introduction of biometrics to login and Quick Access for iPads.

 **29 March 2019**

 **From 15 April 2019, we’re making the following changes to our General Terms and Conditions and Privacy Policy.**

 **General Terms and Conditions:**

The General Terms and Conditions are being amended to state that they incorporate the Privacy Policy.

 **Privacy Policy:**

The Privacy Policy is being amended to include increased clarity regarding the steps we will take if we receive a request for information from the police or any government agency. In these circumstances, we may confirm whether a specified person is or was a customer, but will not provide any other customer information except with a production order, with the customer’s consent, where necessary to prevent or lessen a serious threat to health or safety, or as required by law.

The new General Terms and Conditions and Privacy Policy will come into effect on 15 April 2019 and are available below:

 ** **14 March 2019****

From 28 March 2019 we’re making the following changes to our term sheets for each of Westpac Term PIE Fund, Westpac Term Deposits and the Westpac Notice Saver PIE Fund. To see the full changes please see our updated Term Sheets below.

 **Westpac Term Deposit**

If an early withdrawal is approved by us, in addition to providing us with at least 32 days’ notice, a reduced rate of interest will apply. The calculation that is used to calculate the reduced rate of interest is changing.

Currently the reduced rate of interest is calculated by taking the lesser of:

A) the original agreed interest rate, less **3% per annum** or

B) the interest rate on offer at the time the investment was made for the actual term run through to the date of early withdrawal or a similar term (as we determine in our sole discretion), **less 3% per annum**

The new Term Sheet for Westpac Term Deposits will increase the amount payable on approved term deposit early withdrawals by replacing the references to “less **3% per annum** ” with “less **2% per annum** ”.

Further, the Westpac Term Deposits Term Sheet is changing to clarify that, in the event we agree to an early withdrawal, customers may still cancel the early withdrawal or reduce such early withdrawal amount, prior to the early withdrawal date.

 **Westpac Term PIE Fund**

If an early withdrawal is approved by us, in addition to providing us with at least 32 days’ notice, a reduced rate of return will apply. The calculation that is used to calculate the reduced rate of return is changing.

Currently the reduced rate of return is calculated by taking the lesser of:

A) the original agreed rate of return, less **3% per annum** or

B) the rate of return on offer at the time the investment was made for the actual term run through to the date of early withdrawal or a similar term (as we determine in our sole discretion), less **3% per annum**

The new Term Sheet for Westpac Term PIE Fund will increase the amount payable on approved early withdrawals by replacing the references to “less **3% per annum** ” with “less **2% per annum** ”.

Further, the Westpac Term PIE Fund Term Sheet is changing to clarify that, in the event we agree to an early withdrawal, customers may still cancel the early withdrawal or reduce such early withdrawal amount, prior to the early withdrawal date.

The Term Sheet has also been updated to clarify that customers must provide their IRD number when opening a new Westpac Term PIE Fund account.

 **Westpac Notice Saver PIE Fund**

Approval of an early withdrawal request under the Westpac Notice Saver PIE Fund will only be considered if we agree you are suffering financial hardship.  In this case, no reduction to your return will apply.

For this reason the “Return reduction for early withdrawals” section of the Westpac Notice Saver PIE Fund Term Sheet is being removed from the Westpac Notice Saver PIE Fund Term Sheet.

Please refer to the updated **[Westpac Term PIE Fund Term Sheet](https://www.westpac.co.nz/assets/Uploads/72783JN-13-03-19-Term-PIE-Fund-Term-Sheet.pdf)** , **[Westpac Term Deposit Term Sheet ](https://www.westpac.co.nz/assets/Uploads/72157JN-12-03-19-Term-Deposit-Term-Sheet.pdf)**or the **[Westpac Notice Saver PIE Fund Term Sheet](https://www.westpac.co.nz/assets/Uploads/72934JN-7-03-19-Notice-Saver-PIE-Term-Sheet.pdf)** for more information.

 **4 February 2019**

From 18 February, we’re making the following updates to our General Terms and Conditions.

  * Removing specific references to our Contact Centre opening hours, and instead publishing them on our website.
  * Changing the Contact Centre phone number from 0800 400 600 to 0800 WESTPAC – however both numbers will still work.
  * Removing the wording that advises you that you can delete your mobile phone number in Westpac One. You are only able to edit the mobile number.
  * Removing the words “you can alter, amend, delete a direct debit in Westpac One” – unfortunately this function cannot be performed in Westpac One and can only be carried out by contacting the business that the direct debit was arranged with.

**21 September 2018**

We’re updating our General Terms and Conditions.

We’re continuing our process of simplifying our products and services to make them easier for you to use.

From Monday 8 October 2018 we’re making a change to our General Terms and Conditions. This change explains the process around when we would be able to move you onto a new account.

If there is a reason to move you, we will always contact you in advance to explain why and outline the details of the product or service we have selected for you. You will then have the opportunity to discuss this change and other options with us, prior to any move taking place.

The reasons we may move you are when:

  * a product or service is no longer available, or
  * you are no longer eligible for a product or service, or
  * you’re current product might be adversely affecting you

We are also updating the Electronic Banking Terms to better reflect our current electronic banking functionality.

 **Want to know more?**

Visit the updated [**General Terms and Conditions**](https://www.westpac.co.nz/assets/Who-we-are/About-Westpac-NZ/Westpac-General-Terms-and-Conditions.pdf) now before they come into effect.

 **14 September 2018**

As part of our ongoing process to simplify our products and making them easier to use, we are making some new improvements.

From 28 September 2018, we are changing the name of the Notice Saver PIE account to Notice Saver and making some changes to the terms and conditions that apply to the Westpac Notice Saver PIE Fund (“Fund”). These are set out in the Westpac Notice Saver PIE Fund Term Sheet.

The key changes to the Term Sheet are:

  1. Customers will be able to make withdrawals from their Fund account to any New Zealand bank account.

  2. When customers submit a withdrawal notice, they will no longer receive a lower rate of return on the withdrawal amount.

  3. In some instances we may not be able to meet the aim to offer returns that are higher than that for a term deposit. The term sheet has been amended to reflect this.

  4. There will no longer be a minimum investment amount. However, if a customer’s account balance is $0 (being 0 units), they will not have an interest in the Fund.

  5. When opening an account, the customer and any joint investor must notify us of their IRD number.

Please refer to the updated [Westpac Notice Saver PIE Fund Term Sheet](https://www.westpac.co.nz/assets/Personal/Investment-and-KiwiSaver/Term-Sheets/Westpac-Notice-Saver-PIE-Fund-Term-Sheet.pdf) for further information.

 **31 August 2018**

Changes to when you exchange your foreign cash – International Service Fee

 Effective 15th September 2018, the foreign cash buy fee will be charged. This fee will be $5.00 and is applicable when the bank purchase your foreign cash.

 Please refer to the [Transaction and Service Fees brochure](https://www.westpac.co.nz/assets/Personal/Your-Money-and-Tailored-Packs/Brochures/transaction_service_fees.pdf "Transaction Services and fees brochure") or the [Business Service and Transaction Fees brochure](https://www.westpac.co.nz/page-not-found/ "Business Transaction Services and fees brochure") regarding specific fees for each account.

 **7 August 2018**

The Westpac One iOS App Terms and Conditions are changing, effective from App Version 11.2. The changes will relate to the use of biometrics to login to the application.

 ** ** **8 July 2018******

From 25 July 2018, we’re changing some of our credit card and lending fees.

This includes reducing the annual fee of the Low Rate Mastercard® to $25.00 (paid in two six month instalments of $12.50).

We’re also lowering the personal loan establishment fee from $250 to $100, and removing ATM fees for credit card cash advance withdrawals made at any New Zealand ATM.

You can see all the fee changes below.

**Fee**

| 

**Current Fee**

| 

**New Fee**  
  
---|---|---  
  
Personal Loan establishment fee

| 

$250

| 

$100  
  
Loan payment fail fee

| 

$25

| 

$10  
  
Cash Advance fee (Westpac NZ ATM)

| 

$2

| 

$0  
  
Cash Advance fee (Other NZ Bank ATM)

| 

$2

| 

$0  
  
Cash Advance fee (Via overseas branch or non Global Alliance ATM)

| 

$3

| 

$2  
  
Credit Card over limit fee

| 

$3

| 

$1  
  
Credit Card late payment fee

| 

$12

| 

$8  
  
Replacement card fee

| 

$15

| 

$10  
  
Low Rate Mastercard annual account fee

| 

$65

(Charged 6 monthly at $32.50)

| 

$25

(Charged 6 monthly at $12.50)  
  
Low Rate Mastercard joint card fee

| 

$15 p.a.

| 

$5 p.a.  
  
Low Rate Mastercard additional card fee

| 

$15 p.a.

| 

$5 p.a.  
  
**Westpac Loan Cover  and Westpac Flexicover**

We no longer offer Westpac Loan Cover (personal loan insurance) and Westpac Flexicover (home loan insurance).

Effective from 30 June 2018, Westpac Life -NZ- Limited will no longer offer Westpac Loan Cover and Flexicover insurance. All existing Westpac Loan Cover and Flexicover policies are not affected by this change. However, should you restructure your loan, your policy may be cancelled.

 ** **28 May 2018****

We’re simplifying our transaction accounts, and changing some of the features of the Electronic Account.

From 12 June 2018, we’ll be changing the name of our ‘Electronic’ transaction account to the ‘Westpac Everyday‘ account, and the ‘Access’ and ‘Earner’ transaction accounts will no longer be available as a new account option.

Our customers who currently have Access and Earner accounts will not be affected, and their accounts will continue to operate as usual.

Changes to the Electronic account, renamed the Westpac Everyday account

  * The monthly account maintenance fee of $3.50 – currently waived for customers who choose to receive statements electronically – will be removed.
  * If you choose to receive paperstatements you’ll now be charged a $1.50 paperstatement fee instead of the current monthly account maintenance fee. Receiving your statements electronically will continue to be free.
  * The manual transaction fee of $3.00 per transaction – which covered manual deposits and manual withdrawals – will be replaced by a manual withdrawal fee of $2.50 per transaction. Manual withdrawals include cheques written and withdrawals over the counter. Manual deposits will be free. The manual withdrawal fee is capped at a maximum of $5.00 per month, per account.
  * Anyone 65 years or older will now be eligible for a fee exemption on their Westpac Everyday accounts, which means they won’t pay the paper statement fee or manual withdrawal fee.*

Read more detail on these changes , visit the [Westpac Everyday account](https://www.westpac.co.nz/bank-accounts/transaction-accounts/electronic-account/) or see our [full transaction and service fees](https://www.westpac.co.nz/page-not-found/ "Transaction Services and fees brochure")[](https://www.westpac.co.nz/page-not-found/) to learn more.

 The other terms and conditions which applied to the Electronic account, including Westpac’s General Terms and Conditions, will continue to apply to the Westpac Everyday account.

 _* Note: Service fees will still apply_

 **22 December 2017**

From 8 January 2018, we’re making the following changes to our term sheets for each of Westpac Term Deposits, the Westpac Term PIE Fund, the Westpac Cash PIE Fund and the Westpac Notice Saver PIE Fund.

1\. In the term sheets for all four products, some references to the Code of Banking Practice are being replaced with a reference to Westpac General Terms and Conditions.

We are making this change because of anticipated changes to the Code of Banking Practice which will remove detail around methods of communication with customers. Equivalent provisions have now been inserted into the Westpac General Terms and Conditions.

2\. For the Westpac Cash PIE Fund, new Online Saver PIE accounts are no longer available. For Online Bonus Saver PIE, you can choose to have one or multiple accounts.

3\. For the Westpac Notice Saver PIE Fund, the Funds on Notice rate may no longer be similar to the rate of a term deposit that has the same or similar term to the minimum notice period. The wording in the term sheet will be changed to reflect this.

### Updated documents

The updated Term Sheets are available below.

 ** ** **30 October 2017******

 **We are making some changes to our General Terms and Conditions effective as from 13 November 2017.**

The key changes:

\- the removal of our special answers provision as Westpac is removing our ‘Special Answer’ service for the fast clearance of cheques, effective 13 November 2017;

\- new wording to clarify liability where a customer has used their account for fraudulent or unauthorised transactions;

\- amendments to the international payments provisions clarifying international payment processes, including correspondent and beneficiary bank charges;

\- the exclusion of Westpac One Business from the Electronic Banking Services Terms; and

\- clarification as to the method by which a customer can contact Westpac to close an account.

Our updated General Terms and Conditions are displayed below.

 ** **18 October 2017****

 **Change to Customer Requested Value Transactions Fee**

Effective 1st November 2017, we will increase the Customer Requested Value Transaction Fee, from $10 to $15.  This fee is applied to a business account when a customer requests Westpac to complete a bank transfer between their accounts or to a third party on their behalf. 

Alternatively, customers can avoid this fee by completing the transaction via our on-line banking channels. Please refer to the [Business Service and Transaction Fees](https://www.westpac.co.nz/assets/Personal/Your-Money-and-Tailored-Packs/Brochures/business_transaction_and_service_fees.pdf) brochure regarding specific transaction fees for each account.

 **18 August 2017**

 **Change of Personal Overdraft Establishment Fee for temporary overdrafts**

 **Effective 1 September 2017 we will reduce the Personal Overdraft Establishment Fee  for customers who require a temporary overdraft facility of 45 days or less (temporary overdraft).**

From 1 September 2017, the following fees will apply to temporary overdrafts:

\- For temporary overdrafts of $100 or less, there will be no establishment fee.   
\- For temporary overdrafts in excess of $100, the establishment fee will be $9.

 **1 June 2017**

 **hotpoints® SpendBack™**

 **From 15 June 2017, we’re making some changes to our Conditions of Use that apply to our hotpoints credit cards.**

The changes introduce a new hotpoints redemption function called hotpoints SpendBack.

This function allows customers who use their hotpoints credit card for qualifying purchases (including food and fuel purchases) to redeem their hotpoints to pay back part or all of those purchases, up to three months from the date of the qualifying purchase.

A link to each of our updated conditions of use that apply to hotpoints credit cards and will come into effect on 15 June 2017 are available below.

 ** **9 March 2017****

From 23rd March 2017, we're making some changes to the Conditions of Use that apply to MasterCard BusinessCard/Purchasing Card.

\- The Conditions of Use are being changed remove the Unauthorised transactions insurance policy and the Transit accident insurance policy to reflect that these insurances are no longer a feature of this card. Westpac New Zealand Limited is working with underwriters with a view to reintroducing unauthorised transaction insurance again in due course.

\- The Conditions of Use are also being changed to reflect the changing nature of payment technology in that future payments can be made not only by card by also by way of “other payment instruments” (e.g. paytags, wearable and mobile devices).

The new Conditions of Use will come into effect on 23rd March 2017 and are available below.

 **27 January 2017**

With effect from 1 March 2017 we are making changes to Westpac Credit Card Overseas Travel Insurance policies, which includes making them dementia friendly. Find out more about the policy change [here](https://www.westpac.co.nz/assets/Personal/Credit-Card/PDFs/credit-card-travel-insurance-policy-changes.pdf).

#####  **18 January 2017**

 **Notification of changes to our fees effective 1 February 2017**

From 1 February 2017 we're changing some of our fees on our products and services. A full list of the changes is available [here](https://www.westpac.co.nz/assets/Managing-your-Money/Public-Notices/Changes_to_Fees_1_February_2017.pdf "Fee changes, 1 February 2017").

##### 6 October 2016

 **We are making some changes to our General Terms and Conditions, Consumer Loan Terms and Conditions and the Conditions of Use that apply to Westpac credit cards, debit cards, express card and travel and prepaid card, effective as from 20 October 2016.**

The key changes:

\- we’ve created a new and separate Westpac Privacy Policy which is now available [here](https://www.westpac.co.nz/assets/Personal/Westpac-Privacy-Policy.pdf "Westpac Privacy Policy") at westpac.co.nz or at any Westpac branch;

\- if we change our General Terms and Conditions, or the terms and conditions of Westpac’s services and products, we will give our customers at least 14 days notice in at least one of the following ways: on our website, in branch, within Westpac Online Banking, by public notice, in newspapers or by email or letter;

\- in future Westpac Online Banking customers will receive electronic statements for their online transaction, savings and credit facility accounts, unless they elect to receive statements in paper form. Westpac will give advance notice to customers when paper statements will cease to be provided to them; and

\- wording relating to Cheques and Direct debits sections of our General Terms and Conditions have been updated.

Our updated General Terms and Conditions, each of our updated Conditions of Use and our Consumer Loan documents are displayed below.

Westpac General Terms and Conditions

Westpac Credit Card Conditions of Use

The _World MasterCard_ Account Conditions of Use

The Westpac Airpoints _World MasterCard_ Account Conditions of Use

Westpac Airpoints Credit Card Conditions of Use

The Ultimate Credit Card Account Conditions of Use

Westpac prepaid cards Conditions of Use

Conditions of Use for Westpac Debit MasterCard and Westpac Airpoints Debit MasterCard

Personal Loan Summary – Sample

Personal Loan Terms and Conditions

Overdraft Agreement – Sample

Temporary Overdraft – Sample

Choices Home Loan Summary – Sample

Choices Home Loan Terms and Conditions

Choices Everyday Home Loan Summary – Sample

Choices Everyday Home Loan Terms and Conditions

##### 20 May 2016

 **From 3 June 2016 we’re making some changes to our Conditions of Use that apply to Westpac credit cards, debit cards, and travel & prepaid cards.**

The key changes :

  * Remove reference to specific daily transaction and ATM withdrawal limits in the conditions of use and including a reference that details of such limits are available [here](https://www.westpac.co.nz/daily-transaction-limits/).
  * Provide that following the closure of a hotpoints credit card, any unredeemed hotpoints will expire 10 business days from the date of closure of the hotpoints credit card account.

Our updated Conditions of Use that apply to Westpac credit cards, debit card, travel and prepaid card are below.

Ultimate Credit Card Account Conditions of Use

Westpac General Credit Card Conditions of Use - MasterCard and Visa Cards

Westpac prepaid cards Conditions of Use

 Conditions of Use for Westpac Debit Mastercard and Westpac Airpoints Debit MasterCard

World MasterCard Account Conditions of Use

Westpac Airpoints World MasterCard Account Conditions of Use

Westpac Airpoints Credit Card Conditions of Use

##### 29 April 2016 changes

 **Redeeming hotpoints®**

To give customers the flexibility to choose the best rewards programme for them, when we launched our Airpoints offer, we also introduced the special offer of 180 days to redeem any unused hotpoints when switching to an Airpoints credit card. This special offer expired on 29 April following which the standard 10 business days to redeem unused hotpoints when cancelling or switching a hotpoints credit card will apply. For more information see [Westpac Credit Card Conditions of Use](https://www.westpac.co.nz/assets/Personal/Credit-Card/PDFs/General-Credit-Cards-Conditions-of-Use-Brochure.pdf).

#####  **1 December 2015 changes:**

 **Credit Card Travel Insurance Policy changes**

Some changes have been made to the Overseas Travel Insurance policies that apply to the Westpac Gold Card, Titanium Credit Card, hotpoints Platinum MasterCard and hotpoints  _World MasterCard_  products. To view the policies effective from 1st December, ** [click here](https://www.westpac.co.nz/credit-cards/managing-your-credit-card/credit-card-insurance-cover/)[.](https://www.westpac.co.nz/assets/Who-we-are/About-Westpac-NZ/Westpac-General-Terms-and-Conditions.pdf)**

##### 23 November 2015 changes:

 **We are making some changes to our General Terms and Conditions, effective 23 November 2015.**

The changes clarify certain operational aspects of electronic transactions, in particular relating to automatic payments and direct debits.

##### 26 September 2015 changes:

 **We’re making some changes to the Westpac Debit MasterCard® Conditions of Use. These changes will take effect on 26 September 2015.**

Various sections of the Westpac Debit MasterCard Conditions of Use have been updated to include the conditions of use for Westpac’s new Airpoints™ Debit MasterCard. In particular:

  1. Terms and conditions have been added that specifically relate to Westpac’s new Airpoints product; and
  2. The Westpac Debit MasterCard Conditions of Use will be renamed the Conditions of Use for Westpac Debit MasterCard and Westpac Airpoints Debit MasterCard.

The new Conditions of Use will come into effect on 26 September 2015 are available below.

[Conditions of Use for Westpac Debit MasterCard and Westpac Airpoints Debit MasterCard](https://www.westpac.co.nz/assets/Personal/Bank-Accounts/Debit-MasterCard-Conditions-of-Use.pdf)[](file:///C:/Users/F785431/AppData/Local/Temp/notes2C87F0/Debit%20Card%20Conditions%20of%20Use%20-%20web%20copy%20amends%20100915.docx#_msocom_1)

##### 5 June 2015 changes:

 **From 5 June 2015, we're making some changes to our General Terms and Conditions and the Conditions of Use that apply to Westpac credit cards, debit card, travel and prepaid card and Westpac PayTag® (Terms & Conditions) to make them clearer and more transparent for our customers.**

#### The key changes:

  * provide additional information around when Westpac may vary the Terms & Conditions;
  * identify the website address where details of other relevant documents can be found;
  * confirm the liability of each of Westpac and its customers under the Terms & Conditions;
  * provide more information about how to make a complaint including explaining Westpac’s internal complaint handling processes;
  * stress the need for customers to tell us if any personal details change;
  * confirm the ability of customers to provide Westpac with notices and communications electronically; and
  * provide information to assist customers who may be experiencing financial hardship.

Our updated General Terms & Conditions and the updated Conditions of Use that apply to Westpac credit cards, debit card, travel and prepaid card and Westpac PayTag® are below.

Westpac Credit Card Conditions of Use

Westpac  _World MasterCard_  Account Conditions of Use

Westpac Airpoints™  _World MasterCard_   Account Conditions of Use

Westpac Airpoints™ Credit Card Conditions of Use

General Terms & Conditions

Westpac Debit MasterCard Conditions of Use

Westpac PayTag Terms and Conditions

Westpac prepaid cards Conditions of Use

Westpac Card Conditions of Use

We’re updating our General Terms and Conditions.

We’re continuing our process of simplifying our products and services to make them easier for you to use.

From Monday 8 October 2018 we’re making a change to our General Terms and Conditions. This change explains the process around when we would be able to move you onto a new account.

If there is a reason to move you, we will always contact you in advance to explain why and outline the details of the product or service we have selected for you.  You will then have the opportunity to discuss this change and other options with us, prior to any move taking place.

The reasons we may move you are when:

·        a product or service is no longer available, or

·        you are no longer eligible for a product or service, or

·        you’re current product might be adversely affecting you

We are also updating the Electronic Banking Terms to better reflect our current electronic banking functionality.

Want to know more?

Visit the updated General Terms and Conditions now before they come into effect.

### Westpac New Zealand Limited Constitution 

See the Constitution of Westpac New Zealand Limited [here.](https://www.westpac.co.nz/assets/Who-we-are/About-Westpac-NZ/Constitution/WNZL-Constitution.pdf)

### Westpac New Zealand Limited Board Charter 

See the Board Charter [here.](https://www.westpac.co.nz/assets/Who-we-are/About-Westpac-NZ/Constitution/WNZL-Board-Charter.pdf)
